abbott.in 2017-06-25

# Privacy Policy

Abbott Privacy Policy

This Policy applies to residents of India only.

This Privacy Policy explains how we handle the personal information that you provide to us on Web sites controlled by Abbott (including its subsidiaries and affiliates) which link to this Privacy Policy (referred to as "Abbott Web sites"). This Privacy Policy does not apply to personal information collected from you offline (unless otherwise specified), to Abbott Web sites that do not link to this Privacy Policy, to residents of countries other than or to third-party Web sites to which Abbott Web sites may link. Your use of Abbott Web sites, which link to this Privacy Policy, is subject to this Privacy Policy and the [Terms of Use](http://www.abbott.com/online-terms-and-conditions.html).

Please read this Privacy Policy before using Abbott Web sites or submitting personal information to us.

How does this Privacy Policy define "Personal Information"?

"Personal Information" means information that identifies you or could reasonably be used to identify you and which is submitted to and/or collected by Abbott Web sites and maintained by Abbott in an accessible form. Examples of personal information include your name, your postal address and your telephone number.

How does Abbott collect information online?

Abbott collects information in two ways:

  * Personal Information you submit: Abbott collects personal information that you enter into data fields on Abbott Web sites. For example, you may submit your name, postal address, e-mail address, and/or other information in order to receive information about various subjects, register for Abbott programs, contact Abbott customer service, or respond to Abbott surveys. To protect your privacy, you should not provide Abbott with any information that is not specifically requested or that you do not wish to share.
  * Passive Collection of Unidentifiable Information: Abbott Web sites may collect information about your visits to Abbott Web sites without you actively submitting such information. Unidentifiable information may be collected using various technologies, such as cookies, Internet tags, and web beacons. Your Internet browser automatically transmits to Abbott Web sites some of this unidentifiable information, such as the URL of the Web site you just visited and the browser version your computer is operating. Passive information collection technologies can make your use of Abbott Web sites easier by allowing Abbott to provide better service, customize sites based on consumer preferences, compile statistics, analyze trends, and otherwise administer and improve Abbott Web sites. Certain features of Abbott Web sites may not work without use of passive information collection technologies. Information collected by these technologies cannot be used to identity you without additional identifiable information.

In what circumstances might Abbott collect and use personal information?

Abbott will use the personal information you provide through Abbott Web sites to respond to your questions and to provide you with efficient customer service. After you have entered personal information into a form or data field on an Abbott Web site, Abbott may use certain identifying technologies to allow that Web site to "remember" your personal preferences, such as sections of that Web site that you visit frequently and, if you choose, your user ID. We may also use this personal information for other business purposes, such as to offer you the opportunity to receive notices regarding Abbott’s products or services or to invite you to participate in surveys about our products.

Does Abbott consolidate personal information?

Abbott may consolidate the personal information of customers who use Abbott Web sites. We use this information to help us better design Abbott Web sites and Abbott products, to communicate information to you, to enhance our marketing and research activities, and to facilitate other business functions.

What choices do I have about how Abbott collects and uses personal information about me?

You may always limit the amount and type of personal information that Abbott receives about you by choosing not to enter any personal information into forms or data fields on Abbott Web sites. Some of our online services can only be provided to you if you provide us with appropriate personal information. Other parts of Abbott Web sites may ask whether you wish to opt out or opt into our contact lists for offers, promotions and additional services that may be of interest to you.

You may also be provided with preference questions or preference boxes allowing you to indicate that you do not want Abbott Web sites to use tracking technologies, such as cookies, to "remember" your personal information, such as user IDs or mailing addresses, on return visits. However, Abbott Web sites that use tracking technologies to collect unidentifiable information do not generally provide you with the ability to opt out of the tracking technologies. Some Internet browsers allow you to limit or disable the use of tracking technologies that collect unidentifiable information.

Who will have access to personal information about me?

Personal information can be accessed by a restricted number of Abbott employees, by certain companies, third party processing, storage, etc. with which Abbott may conduct joint programs, and by individuals and entities with whom Abbott contracts to carry out business activities for Abbott. We train our employees about the importance of privacy and how to handle and manage customer data appropriately and securely. Also, it is Abbott’s practice to notify you if you are registering for a program which is conducted in conjunction with another company that may require access to your personal information. In addition, Abbott’s practice is to require its contractors to keep your personal information confidential and to use personal information only to perform functions for Abbott.

Does Abbott share personal information with third parties?

As a general rule, Abbott does not share your personal information with third parties, unless it is necessary to conduct a joint program or to carry out a program or activity (such as data storage, analysis or processing) through a contractor/third party. For this purpose, Abbott/third party may transfer his information outside of India. Where required by law, Abbott will not disclose your personal information to third parties for those third parties’ marketing purposes, unless you have been provided with an opportunity to opt into or opt out of this disclosure. However, if Abbott sells one of its product lines or divisions, your personal information may be transferred to the buyer so that the buyer can continue to provide you with information and services. If Abbott provides your personal information to individuals and entities which assist us with our business activities, it is Abbott’s practice to require those individuals and entities to keep your personal information confidential and to use your personal information only to perform functions for Abbott. Abbott reserves the right to disclose your personal information to respond to authorized information requests from government authorities, to address national security situations, or when otherwise required by law.

How does Abbott secure Personal Information?

It is Abbott’s practice to secure each web page that collects personal information; however, the confidentiality of personal information transmitted over the Internet cannot be guaranteed. We urge you to exercise caution when transmitting personal information over the Internet, especially personal information related to your health. Abbott cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will not gain access to your personal information; therefore, when submitting personal information to Abbott Web sites, you must weigh both the benefits and the risks. In addition, Abbott Web sites covered by this Privacy Policy will display a warning whenever you link to a Web site that is not controlled by Abbott or subject to an Abbott Privacy Policy; you should check the privacy policies of such third-party Web sites before submitting personal information. Personal information is stored in Abbott common servers and Abbott has reasonable security Practices and Procedures for securing such information.

How does Abbott protect the privacy of children?

Abbott does not knowingly collect or use any personal information from children (we define "children" as minors younger than 13) on Abbott Web sites. We do not knowingly allow children to order our products, communicate with us, or use any of our online services. If you are a parent and become aware that your child has provided us with information, please contact us using one of the methods specified below, and we will work with you to address this issue.

How may I correct personal information or delete it from current customer records?

You may request to remove your personal information from our current customer records or to amend your personal information. Please notify us of your wishes by contacting us in one of the ways specified below. For our record keeping purposes, we will retain certain personal information you submit.

How can I contact Abbott?

If you have questions about the use, amendment, or deletion of personal information that you have provided to us, or if you would like to opt out of future communications from an Abbott business or a particular Abbott program, please contact us by clicking on the "Contact Us" link on the Web site you are visiting or by e-mailing us at [webmaster@abbott.co.in](mailto:webmaster@abbott.co.in) Alternatively, you may send a letter to the following address:

Abbott India Limited  
Public Affairs Department  
3-4, Corporate Park, Sion-Trombay Road  
Mumbai – 400 071

In all communications to Abbott, please include the e–mail address used for registration (if applicable), the Web site address or the specific Abbott program to which you provided personal information), and a detailed explanation of your request. If you would like to delete or amend your personal information and are contacting us by e-mail, please put "Deletion Request" or "Amendment Request, as applicable, in the subject line of the e-mail. We will do our best to respond to all reasonable requests in a timely manner.

How will I know whether Abbott has updated this policy?

Abbott reserves the right to amend this Privacy Policy without prior notice to reflect technological advancements, legal and regulatory changes and good business practices. If Abbott changes its privacy practices, a new Privacy Policy will reflect those changes and the effective date of the revised Privacy Policy will be set forth in this paragraph. We recommend that you visit this Policy every time you are about to provide Abbott with your personal information.
